Lê Nguyễn Đăng Khoa

109/13A Huỳnh Thị Hai, Ward Tân Chánh Hiệp, District..12

८ 0934995729 ■ leekhoa993@gmail.com **%** https://fb.com/leekhoa.lenguyendangkhoa

INTRODUCTION

I'm a System Engineer, specialized in Linux operating system. I have more than 6 years of work experience in System Engineering and Administration (both infrastructure/networking and IT applications). Currently, I work as a DevOps to automate infrastructure/system on-cloud. I have knowledge of integrating automation build, test, and deploying applications into Jenkins CI/CD. I have experience and strong at System Linux and other systems using Docker.

I like to research and work with new systems and new technologies. I always use my free time to learning new technologies and research them. I having a huge passion for Linux and the open-source community, enthusiastically, progressive. I'm interesting and focusing research on Linux systems, I hope I can become a good DevOps engineer.

EDUCATION

FPT JETKING 09/2013 - 09/2015

Network infrastructure management (Network and hardware)

Grade A. Average score 7.

- I have studied and researched networks, hardware, and little about language programming. I have archived high results in my learning process.
- Project learned: CCNA, LPI 1,2& advance, Firewall,...
- My graduation project is a design network and server system for medium enterprises, it is rated quite well in terms of ideas and techniques.

Nguyễn Tất Thành University

09/2011 - 09/2014

Infomation Technology

KNOWLEDGE & SKILLS

	System / DevOps //		
CI/CD	Jenkins CI/CD, Github action, Gitlab, Bitbucket Pipeline		
Database	Mysql, sqlite3, MS SQL, MariaDB, Postgres, MongoDB		
Automation tools	Vagant, Ansible, Terraform		
Cluster	OpenShift, Kubenetes, Docker Swarm		
Cloud	AWS, GCP, Azure		
Virtualization	OpenVZ, Proxmox, VMware Esxi, Virtualbox, Docker.		
Scripting	Python, Groovy, bash shell, awk, sed.		
Monitoring	Cacti, Zabbix, CheckMK, Grafana/Prometheus, Cabot/Graphite.		
//	OS & Networking //		
Mail server	Postfix, Mdeamon, Dovecot, squirrelmail.		
Web server	Apache, Nginx, Tomcat, HAproxy, Nginx reverse proxy.		
Network	CCNA, OSI network layer, TCP/IP		
Linux system			

Other System

CoreDNS + Etcd, Parse Server + Parse Dashboard.

WORK EXPERIENCE

TMA Solution 02/2021 - Now

Senior System (DevOps).

Join Project - Network management system (Cloud solution).

- This project focuses on providing a multi-tenant cloud solution for NMS network management system.
- Build up tools and services for system monitoring and CI/CD.
- Build & configuration datapond with source code ParseDashboard.
- Implement and maintaining CI/CD leading to an improvement in the time to ship new feature releases.
- Write and edit script automation to upgrade & downgrade tenants.
- Deploy instance in AWS EC2 when have requested.
- Support customer/dev/QA solving issues about tenants, docker platform,.....

Join Project - Application component management (On-Premise solution).

- Working on 5G-Oran technology.
- Define stage and step in pipeline to build/test/deliver each component.
- Create a job in Jenkins to CI/CD for each component.
- Monitor and send mail alert of process Jenkins to email.

VNG Cloud 05/2018 - 02/2021

System Engineer (SysOps)

Join support, build, manage, monitor server for all systems of product VNG: Server Game, Storage, Zalo Team, system IT helpdesk,...

- Plain for a provisioning server, install the server, deploy service.
- Setup OS, configuring OS, optimize OS as a requirement of production.
- Monitoring and manage all system servers and infrastructure for Datacenter have more than 10.000 physical servers and about 3000 virtual machines.
- Automation deploy OS via template by a bash shell script.
- Configure network and service as a request from system engineer of product.
- Build, monitoring, maintenance & operation camera system for DC. Use NAS technologies for storing data, backup, log, and monitoring.
- Optimize & operation an access control system for DC.
- Plain for optimizing and improve the system.
- Support product resolve and troubleshoot problems.
- Deploy some script automation by bash shell and python.
- Operation tool monitoring: cacti, checkMK, Zabbix, Splunk,....

Luu Trữ Số - 123HOST 04/2016 - 05/2018

IT System Support

Join support team, configuring, monitoring network and infrastructure for the system. Configuring the system, installing service as request.

- Support customer use service Domain/Hosting/Server/VPS and more related service. Troubleshooting problems of customers when use service.
- Customer consulting, install the service web app, mail server,.... in Linux operating system as required from customer.
- Configuring, manage, optimize server hosting: cPanel, DirectAdmin, Plesk,...
- Configuring, manage, optimize virtual systems: OpenVZ, VMware ESXi, Proxmox,...
- Research and propose solutions for optimizing and improve system hosting/VPS.
- Design, deploy and maintain web, mail, app service: LAMP stack, LEMP stack, Nginx reverse proxy, HAproxy, postfix dovecot, SquirrelMail, MDaemon,....
- Monitoring, administrating system server of customers in the datacenter.
- Operating system DDOS protection, load balancing: WAF, IP Filtering, proxy,...

Tâm Việt Dental Clinic 09/2015 - 08/2016

Take on role IT helpdesk. Design and configuring the network, installing and maintaining server local. Install application for the user.

- Build, configuring, and installing local network system for clinic.
- Monitoring network for medical equipment.
- Administrating website system of clinic
- Report and propose solutions to replace hardware and maintenance IT devices.
- Configuring software in the medical device, server, and pc for the user.

CERTIFICATE

Python foundation		
Cpanel		
IPv6 Certificate		
LPI 1&2. LPI Advance		
CCNA		

INTERESTS

- Researching open-source projects & new technologies.
- Repair and Restoration motor engine. Research about Engine.
- Playing billiards, Game MOBA, swimming, playing guitar, listening to music, etc.